on today's video we are going to
make the most luxurious chocolate
ice cream you're probably ever going
to eat there's a fair few components
to it but it's all relatively
simple so let's get on and make
[Music] it now before we go too far into
this ice cream video for the first time
on this channel I want to ask something of
you all of you watching if you're an animal
this might hit home very very good friends of ours
have a dog called Maisy she's only 2 years old she
is unfortunately got problems with her back legs
which means she really struggles to walk at only
2 years old you can understand that there's a
lot of life left for her but the operations she
needs are going to cost $10,000 Canadian dollar
now our friends are a single learning family one
of them is at school fulltime and the other one
works for an airline I'm asking you personally
if you can help out please head over to their
GoFundMe page and offer any support that you can
I've donated from the business my wife has also
donated individually even if it's $1 every dollar
will help get Maisy the care she needs to have a
better life thanks for listening to this pledge
and let's get on with the ice cream chocolate
ice cream surprisingly difficult to do it well
there are are so many like there's probably more
vanilla bad vanilla recipes but closely followed
by bad chocolate ice cream recipes but once you
start getting into the INRI of making your own
ice cream and how to make it better than any
ice cream that anyone has ever given you before
we need to start breaking down why some ice cream
is better than others and this is where chocolate
ice cream becomes quite complex there's a fair
few ingredients that are going into this there's
not that many substitutions available to you so
we've got standard sugar skin milk powder this is
0.1% fat milk powder no you can't use whole milk
powder dextrose corn syrup golden syrup I'm using
golden syrup in this one because the flavor or the
caramel note flavor of the golden syrup actually
is what builds this ultimate luxury chocolate
ice cream vanilla extract and then we've got
high quality milk chocolate and high quality cocoa
powder I'm using giradelli dutched here please use
a good quality one you've got caca Barry that's
really good obviously valona that's excellent
you've got gards Rouge which is also incredibly
good giradelli dutched really really good less
chat more make what we going to need because
there's a fair bit going into this I'm going to
put it up on the screen for you I will put the
cup measurements next to the gram measurements
but I say this I do say this a bit try and get a
gram scale they're so cheap these days and that
is what's going to take your ice cream from pretty
good to excellent because you can actually weigh
out the components accurately so for the ultimate
chocolate ice cream you're going to need 450 G of
2% milk 550 g of whipping cream at 33 to 35% fat
140 g of sugar 44 G of dexr 10 G of corn syrup
or golden syrup 40 G of skim milk powder 50 g
of cocoa powder 40 G of milk chocolate 2 G of
stabilizer or stabilizer blend and two gram of
vanilla extract there we go if you're brand new
to making homemade ice cream this is going to be
a difficult one there's a fair few ingredients but
it is actually quite straightforward to make so
let's get started I'll talk as we go 450 G of uh
milk 550 g of our whipping cream into this we're
going to put 10 G of of our golden syrup you can
buy golden syrup in Walmart Safeway any if you're
in the UK any shop known to man what we have here
is our skin milk powder and our sugar doesn't
make any difference if it goes in one container
or another there's no stabilizer in this mix here
so doesn't make any difference what we can do is
just put the whole lot in whisk that together
because we want the surface of our Dairy clear
to put the other ingredients in now what we have
here is probably the only optional ingredient in
this is lein and a mulier sunflower Lin soy lerin
doesn't matter lerin is what is in egg yolks and
that is an emulsifying ingredient which combines
fat and water together and keeps them there you
don't need this because chocolate has less of
thin in it as well but we're going for the best
chocolate ice cream that you're ever going to eat
so why not if you decide to use it then use 3 G of
your lein I've got in here with my stabilizer and
my dextr this is my own stabilizer blend 422 with
the stabilizer with the emulsifier stabilizer
we're just going to stir this together in it
goes stir that together we've only got a few other
ingredients to go in here vanilla is going to go
in right at the end we've got our cocoa powder
here which is our giradelli dutched excellent
cocoa powder we can just put that in and slowly
stir that it'll be quite difficult to get that
mixed in just keep stirring it it will it will go
and as we heat it up that will help the fat in the
cocoa will start to break down and mix into your
Dairy so with the cocoa powder mixed in you'll see
it will kind of look mtled that surface that's
because the cocoa powder hasn't broken down yet
all right and finally the chocolate you can just
put the chocolate in here cut it up don't cut it
up doesn't make any difference it will just take
longer for that chocolate to melt down as we heat
it up so let's get on hob so with our pan on the
hob we're now just going to bring this up to the
temperature required by our stabilizer which is
85c 180f or 185f whatever it is so as you start
coming up to temperature you can see all the
cocoa powder is completely modified together
so we've got a really nice homogeneous mix here
if you don't have a thermometer then what you
need to do is look at the edges we don't want
to boil any ice cream mix ever if if you don't
use a stabilizer then you just need to heat it
up to emulsify the ingredients and homogenize
the mix but I do recommend you use one ideally
we're looking for about 3 to 5% of evaporation
rate quick mention about the evaporation rate we
do that because in a pasteurizer in a commercial
environment by pasteurizing a base you are
bringing it up to temperature and that the machine
has a paddle inside and a heating element heats
up stirs it agitates it it homogenizes the base
as it pasteurizes it at the same time during that
we get around 5% evaporation rate some pasteurizes
you can actually set the evaporation rate and
it weighs the base as it goes through at home
we don't have that luxury we can if you measure
by grams weigh all of your ingredients before you
put it on a hob and then measure it after that
gives you the percentage evaporation by weight
the purpose of the evaporation is to help thicken
the base by removing excess water the excess water
removal also AIDS Ice Crystal formation stops
that excess water creating large ice crystals
as it freezes we use the stabilizers on this
science-based channel to allow us to bypass some
of that but you will always get a better result if
you allow a 3 to 5% evaporation of your ice cream
base finally before we move on to the next stage
yes you can do this for your ninja creamy as well
this will work perfectly as it is no adjustments
required all you need to do is let it age this
is another super important part of this ultimate
chocolate ice cream aging a base increases flavors
allows flavors to combine to create something
super special we've been off the hob for about
5 minutes and it's it's cooled down probably
around the 60 Centigrade range something like
that what we can do now is put in our vanilla
extract we don't put it in while it's on the hob
because around 80° the alcohol starts to
evaporate and along with that we lose a
lot of the vanilla flavor so add extract
to a cool or cooling base not to a hot
place so with all of those ingredients in we can
now put it in a container and we can pop this in
the fridge you got two options here you can cool
it down in a nice bath nice and quick and then
put it in the refrigerator overnight or you can
just leave it out for half an hour and then put
it in refrigerator it's 33° C here today I'm
not using up ice to cool this down nice and
quick I'm going to leave it out with the lid on
for 30 minutes then I'm going to pop it in the
fridge leave it in the fridge for a minimum
of 12 hours this is what's going to make the
difference all right don't rush this one this
one make the day before Churn it the day after
[Music]
there you go chocolate ice cream not as easy as
people or some people seem to think chocolate
ice cream is one of the hardest ice creams
to get right it goes hard because there's
additional fats in there it's a powder so
it's absorbing water and ultimately what it
does is creat something that tastes good but
is generally quite hard to scoop being an ice
cream Channel we know that we can adjust the
softness texture with things like some types
of sugar and stabilizers and ulfi and gives
us this it's hot today it's another 33 Cade
day what's that like early '90s everything
is melting super fast you can't avoid ice
cream melting don't ask me how to stop it
melting I'm going to tell you the same thing
it's ice cream it should melt let's see what
this chocolate ice cream tastes like oh yeah
I don't often just eat the ice
[Music] cream straight away
but man that was good good ice cream what's
what's different between using cocoa powder on
its own and cocoa powder and actual chocolate
totally different flavor profiles this is
valona tanara 33% 33% 33% uh cocoa solid
so this is a a solid milk chocolate the
giradelli cocoa powder also gives you
a milk chocolate profile flavor so what
you get is this combination of different milk
chocolates combined to create something really
really nice the additional chocolate gives you
higher solids content higher fat means less
cream that we can use I mean this is you know
this is not a low fat ice cream I'm not going
to lie you can play with loads of different types
of chocolate different flavors of chocolate you
can make it with mint chocolate and add a touch
of mint to it you can do it with orange and any
chocolate you like go back and watch there's
cocoa poad everywhere go back and watch some
of the other episodes of the chocolate series I
just it's my favorite flavor chocolate ice cream
it's it's absolutely destroyed by most ice cream
scoop shops ice creameries they absolutely butcher
it because they don't care they buy the cheapest
cocoa powder they can get and make a chocolate
ice cream out of it and hope they taste good you
know ultimately if you're a scoop shop owner use
something good for [__] sake use something
like valona gards giradelli caca Barry all of
these will give you head and shoulders above
everyone else chocolate ice cream don't be a
cheap ass consumers are paying a lot of money
for ice cream these days so give them something
worth eating quick reminder please please help out
Maisy with her operation Link in the description
below and thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe see you next time
[Music]